Guide to the Jascha Heifetz Collection ARS.0046
Archive of Recorded Sound
- 12" Sound Discs, 78 rpm discs
  - Instantaneous Recordings, 78 and 33 rpm discs
    - Box 20, 78 rpm discs
      - Rossini, Gioacchino, 1792-1868. Barbiere di Siviglia. Largo al factotum; arr., 1944 August 21; Single-sided 12" glass-based instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 20, Disc 854)
        In attached envelope: labels, detached from disc (one label with typescript and handwritten information as follows: R-4035 Aug. 21, 1944 Phillip Morris Rehearsal Part 1 [Speed] 33)
        Titles on label/disc: “Figaro” from Barber of Seville Telephone Hr
        National Broadcasting Co. Inc.: R-4035[?]
      - United Jewish Appeal Program [in six parts], 1941 May 7; 1941 May 26; 3 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs (Box 20, Disc 855-857)
        Information in typescript and stamped on labels
        National Broadcasting Co. Inc.: 30469, 30470, 30471, 30472, 30473, 30474
        May 7, 1941 in typescript on label; May 26, 1941 stamped on label
      - Command Performance [in four parts], 1942 July 14; 2 12" glass-based instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs (Box 20, Disc 858-859)
        In attached envelope: label, detached from disc 859
        Armed Forces Radio Service (AFRS) variety show featuring Edward Arnold, Paul Douglas, Ethel Waters, Richard Haydn, Jascha Heifetz, Jack Benny, Reginald Beane, Laura Vaughns, Ella Lashley, Emanuel Bey, and Constantin Bakaleinikoff conducting the RKO Studio Orchestra
        National Broadcasting Co. Inc.: [no numbers assigned]
      - Soldiers in Greasepaint [in ten parts], 1943 November 25; 5 12" glass-based instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs (Box 20, Disc 860-864)
        In attached envelopes: labels, detached from discs
        United Service Organizations (USO) Thanksgiving special, hosted by Jack Benny and Bob Hope, with Al Jolson, Fredric March, Brigadier General Joseph Byron, Rear Admiral Louis E. Denfeld, Jascha Heifetz, Martha Raye, Kay Francis, Carole Landis, Pat O'Brien, Judith Anderson, Jackie Heller, Mitzi Mayfair, Merle Oberon, Jerry Colonna, Andy Devine, Jim Burke, Jinx Falkenburg, Faye McKenzie, Anna Lee, John Garfield, Frances Langford, and the Thomas Peluso Orchestra
    - Box 21, 78 rpm discs
      Cantelli, Guido; Bell Telephone Hour Orchestra; McCormack, John; Voorhees, Donald; Kreisler, Fritz; Casals, Pablo; Kreisler, Hugo; Thibaud, Jacques; Cortot, Alfred; Bay, Emanuel; Benoist, André; Toscanini, Arturo; New York Philharmonic; Barbirolli, John, Sir; Primrose, William; London Symphony Orchestra; Kroll, William; London Philharmonic Orchestra; Falkenstein, George; Lamson, Carl; O’Brien, Vincent; Sandor, Arpad
      - [Bell] Telephone Hour, 1948 April 19; 3 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs (Box 21, Disc 865-867)
        Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 77, D major -- Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946. Canciones populares españolas. Jota
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; [sides 1-4: Bell Telephone] Orchestra; Donald Voorhees, conductor
        National Broadcasting Co. Inc.: EXCERPT [sides of discs 865 and 866 numbered 1-4; disc 867 is single-sided and unnumbered]
      - Bell Telephone Hour, 1950 May 1; 1950 May 8; 3 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs (Box 21, Disc 868-870)
        [Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; Bell Telephone Orchestra; Donald Voorhees, conductor]
        National Broadcasting Co. Inc.: [discs numbered on both sides Part 1 through Part 6]
        From label: May 1st, 1950 9:00 - 9:30 P.M. Net; Dubbed 5/8/50
      - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Trios, piano, strings, no. 1, op. 49, D minor, 4 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs (Box 21, Disc 871-874)
        Information handwritten in ink on labels
        Performed by Alfred Cortot, piano; Jacques Thibaud, violin; Pablo Casals, violoncello
        Sound Services Inc.: [discs numbered on both sides I through VIII]
      - Carnegie Hall, 3 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs (Box 21, Disc 875-877)
        Information handwritten on discs
        Title handwritten on discs 876 and 877: Part - 1
        Soundcraft: [no numbers assigned]
      - Castelnuovo-Tedesco, Mario, 1895-1968. Alt Wien. Alt Wien; arr. -- Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Concertos, violins (2), string orchestra, BWV 1043, D minor, 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 21, Disc 878)
        Handwritten on label in ink: Piano part of Alt Wien - Castelnuovo; Bach Double concerto last mov. 2nd violin
        Handwritten on sleeve: Bay
      - Missing 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 21, Disc 879)
        All information from collection inventory: Dinicu, Grigoraș. Hora staccato
        [T900]
      - Missing 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 21, Disc 880)
        All information from collection inventory: Debussy [unspecified]
        [T943]
      - Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Tragische Ouvertüre -- Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 77, D major, 4 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs (Box 21, Disc 881-884)
        Information etched in discs: Brahms Overture Toscanini; Brahms Concerto Heifetz Toscanini
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; unidentified orchestra; Arturo Toscanini, conductor
      - Symphony [unspecified], 6 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs (Box 21, Disc 885-890)
        Information etched in discs as follows:
        Disc 885: H - T, second movement, third movement
        Disc 886: H - T, second movement, third movement
        Disc 887: symphony
        Disc 888: symphony
        Disc 889: symphony
        Disc 890: symphony
      - Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Nocturnes, orchestra. Fêtes -- Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918. Nocturnes, orchestra. Nuages, 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 21, Disc 891)
        Handwritten on label in ink: Debussy Fetes Toscanini [one side]; Debussy Nuages Toscanini [reverse side]
        Performed by unidentified orchestra; Arturo Toscanini, conductor
      - Excerpts [unidentified], 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 21, Disc 892)
        Handwritten on label in ink: Excerpts - of Radio - [Broadcasts?] - Bach, etc. samples
      - B-cast [broadcast] programs [unidentified], 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound disc (Box 21, Disc 893)
        Handwritten on label in ink: B-cast programs Philharmonia orchestra etc. [one side]; Bach solos Radio B-cast of part of Carmen etc. [reverse side]
        Etched in one side of disc: Bach
      - Singing and conversation, 2 12" instantaneous 78 rpm sound discs (Box 21, Disc 894a-894b)
        Etched in disc 894a: Elsa’s singing [one side]; [Jascha] Heifetz conversation [reverse side]
        Handwritten on sleeve of disc 894b: Poly-waly doodle (off radio?)
      - Jascha Heifetz, 12" 33 rpm vinyl sound disc (Box 21, Disc 900)
        Title information from labels: [side A:] Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Introduction et rondo capriccioso -- Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Havanaise -- [untitled]; [side B:] Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908. Zigeunerweisen -- Halvorsen, Johan, 1864-1935. Passacaglia, violin, viola, G minor -- Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937. Tzigane -- Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957. Musik zu Shakespeare’s Viel Lärmen um nichts. Gartenszene -- Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957. Musik zu Shakespeare’s Viel Lärmen um nichts. Holzapfel und Schlehwein
        Handwritten in pencil on disc jacket [in separate sleeve]: April 30, 70 270 N. Beverly Dr. -- $6.30
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; London Philharmonic Orchestra (Sir John Barbirolli, conductor); London Symphony Orchestra (Sir John Barbirolli, conductor); William Kroll, banjo/fiddle; Emanuel Bay, piano; William Primrose, viola; Arpad Sandor, piano
        MJA: MJA 5003-A1, MJA 5003-B1 [matrix]; K-2095, K-2094 [additional nos. etched in disc]
      - Fritz Kreisler, 2 12" instantaneous 33 rpm sound discs (Box 21, Disc 901-902)
        [side one:] Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Lieder ohne Worte, piano, op. 62. Nr. 1; arr. -- Krakauer, Alexander, 1866-1894. Du guater Himmelvater -- Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Alt-Wiener Tanzweisen. Liebesleid -- Drigo, Riccardo, 1846-1930. Millions d’Arlequin. Sérénade; arr. -- Dawes, Charles Gates, 1865-1951. Melody, violin, piano -- Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924. Orange blossoms. Kiss in the dark -- [side two:] Poldini, Ede, 1869-1957. Marionettes. Poupée valsante -- Scott, Cyril, 1879-1970. Cherry ripe; arr. -- Kramer, A. Walter (Arthur Walter), 1890-1969. Entr'acte -- Brandl, Johann, 1835-1913. Liebe Augustin. Du alter Stefansturm; arr. -- Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Zigeunermelodien. Als die alte Mutter; arr. -- [side three:] Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Arlésienne. Suite. Adagietto -- Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Polichinelle -- White, Clarence Cameron, 1880-1960. Bandanna sketches. Chant -- Koschat, Thomas, 1845-1914. Kärntner Volksweisen. Verlassen bin i; arr. -- Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Aucassin and Nicolette -- Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Apple blossoms. I’m in love; arr. -- Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Toy soldiers march -- [side four:] Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Alt-Wiener Tanzweisen. Schön Rosmarin -- Logan, Frederic Knight, 1871-1928. Pale moon -- Heuberger, Richard, 1850-1914. Opernball. Im chambre séparée -- Kreisler, Fritz, 1875-1962. Caprice viennois -- Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Sonatina, violin, piano, op. 100, G major. Larghetto; arr. -- Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. Cavalleria rusticana. Intermezzo; arr.
        In typescript on yellow labels: Fritz Kreisler Side one; Side two; Side three; Side four
        Handwritten on yellow labels in blue ink: [side one:] Song without words - [illegible name] (George Falkenstein at piano) -- Paradise (Viennese folk song) Krakauer-Kreisler -- Liebeslied (Hugo Kreisler) Kreisler-Fritz at piano -- Serenade (H Kreisler - cello) Drigo Fritz at piano -- Melody - General Dawes - Lamson at piano -- A kiss in the dark - Herbert (Lamson) [followed by additional writing crossed out] -- [side two:] Waltzing doll - Poldini - Kreisler -- Cherry ripe - Scott -- Entre’acte - Walter Kramer -- The old refrain - Kreisler -- Songs my mother taught me - Dvorak-Kreisler (Lamson at piano) -- [side three:] Lamsen on piano [written vertically on one side of label on sides three and four] Adagietto (from “L’Arlesienne”) - Bizet -- Polichinelle Serenade - Kreisler -- Nobody Knows de Trouble I’ve Seen - White -- Forsaken - Koschat - Winternitz -- Aucassin & Nicolette - Kreisler -- I’m in Love (from “Apple Blossoms”) Hugo Kreisler arr. by Fritz -- Toy Soldiers March - Kreisler -- [side four:] Schon Rosmarin - Kreisler (Falkenstein - piano) -- Pale Moon - Logan - Kreisler -- Midnight Bells - Heuberger - Kreisler -- Caprice Viennois - Kreisler (Falkenstein) -- Indian Lament - Dvorak-Kreisler (O’Brien - piano) -- Ave Maria - Mascagni (O’Brien - piano) (McCormack with Kreisler) Performed by Fritz Kreisler, violin/piano; George Falkenstein, piano; Hugo Kreisler, violoncello; Carl Lamson, piano; Vincent O’Brien, piano; John McCormack, tenor
        Capitol Records: [no numbers assigned to discs]
      - Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 64, E minor, 1954 March 14; 12" instantaneous 33 rpm sound disc (Box 21, Disc 903)
        Side 1: 1st movement; side 2: 2nd and 3rd movements
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; New York Philharmonic; Guido Cantelli, conductor
        Carnegie Hall Recording Co.: [no number assigned to disc]
        Disc labeled: Station WCBS-FM March 14 1954
      - Jascha Heifetz/Fritz Kreisler, 12" instantaneous 33 rpm sound disc (Box 21, Disc 904)
        [Heifetz side:] Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Nocturnes, piano, op. 9. No. 2; arr. -- Goldmark, Carl, 1830-1915. Concertos, violin, orchestra, no. 1, op. 28, A minor. Andante -- [Kreisler side:] Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Ungarische Tänze. Nr. 17 -- Scott, Cyril, 1879-1970. Pieces, piano, op. 47. Lotus land
        Information in typescript and printed on labels
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin, and André Benoist, piano; Fritz Kreisler, violin, and Arpad Sandor, piano
        [Heifetz side, in typescript:] 74616 & 74764 Victor; [Kreisler side:] 6706-A RCA Victor
        Printed on label: recorded by KFAC, “The Music Station,” Los Angeles
      - Command Performance, 12" instantaneous 33 rpm sound disc (Box 21, Disc 905)
        Information handwritten on disc, as follows: PGM 22 PT 2 COMMAND PERFORMANCE SIDE [one side labeled Side 2; reverse side has no number]
        National Hollywood Silver Seal: [no number assigned to disc]
      - [Bell] Telephone Hour Exc., 1954 January 25; 1954 January 28; 12" instantaneous 33 rpm sound disc (Box 21, Disc 906)
        Information in typescript on disc
        Titles on labels: Concerto No. 5 in A Minor -- “Melody” & Polonaise in D Major
        National Broadcasting Company Inc. (NBC Orthacoustic): CT 98
        From label: January 28, 1954 Dubb
      - [Bell] Telephone Hour, 1953 October 12; 1953 October 18; 12" instantaneous 33 rpm sound disc (Box 21, Disc 907)
        Information in typescript and handwritten in pencil on disc
        Side one: Muy mal! Microphone? [handwritten]
        National Broadcasting Company Inc. (NBC Orthacoustic): CT 1303
        From label: 10-18-53 [dub date?]
      - Strauss [unspecified], 12" instantaneous 33 rpm sound disc (Box 21, Disc 908)
        Information handwritten in blue ink on label, as follows: XI Jenkins singing - also other side This is Strauss
        Presto Recording Company
  - Test Pressings, 78 rpm discs
    - Box 6: Gramophone, 78 rpm discs
      Barbirolli, John, Sir; London Philharmonic Orchestra; Sandor, Arpad
      - Hummel, Johann Nepomuk, 1778-1837. Rondos, piano, op. 11, E♭ major; arr., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 6, Disc 197)
        Title and performer information in typescript on label
        Gramophone: 2B.6043-1[square]
      - Clérambault, Louis-Nicolas, 1676-1749. Cantates françoises, livre 2. Léandre et Héro. Ritournelle., 1934 February 21; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 6, Disc 198)
        In typescript on label: 21-2-34 Largo on G string (Clerambault/arr. Dandelot)
        Gramophone: 2B.6052-2.[square]
      - Albéniz, Isaac, 1860-1909. Suite española, no. 1. Sevilla; arr., 1934 February 21; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 6, Disc 199)
        In typescript on label: 21-2-34. Sevilla. (Albeniz-Heifetz) violin solo with piano
        Gramophone: 2B.6056-2.[square]
      - Paganini, Nicolò, 1782-1840. Caprices, violin, M.S. 25. No. 24; arr., 1934 February 21; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 6, Disc 200-201)
        In typescript on label: 21-2-34. Caprice no. 24 part 1, part 2 (Paganini-Auer) violin solo with piano
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz; [Arpad Sandor], piano
        Gramophone: 2B.6057-2.[square], 2B.6058-2.[square]
      - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonaten und Partiten, violin, BWV 1001-1006. Partita, no. 2. Chaconne., 1934 February 23; 3 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 6, Disc 202-204)
        In typescript on labels: 23-2-34. Chaconne [Parts 1-3] (Bach)
        Gramophone: 2B.6064-1.[square], 2B.6065-1[square], 2B.6066-1[square]
      - Wieniawski, Henri, 1835-1880. Scherzo-tarantelle., 1934 February 23; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 6, Disc 205)
        In typescript on label: 23-2-34. Scherzo Tarantelle. (Wieniewski)
        Gramophone: 2B.6067-2.[square]
      - Dohnányi, Ernő, 1877-1960. Ruralia hungarica, violin, piano. Andante rubato, alla zingaresca, 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 6, Disc 206)
        In typescript on label: Ruralia Hungarica, Op. 32, No. 2, Gypsy Andante (Dohnanyi)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz; [unidentified pianist?]
        Gramophone: 2B.6102-3[square], DA.2220 [in typescript on label]
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, violin, orchestra, K. 219, A major., 1934 February 23; 8 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 6, Disc 207-214)
        In typescript on labels: 23-2-34. Violin concerto in A Major [Parts 1-8] (Mozart) Violin solo with orchestra
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz; unidentified orchestra
        Gramophone: 2B.6801-2[square], 2B.6802-1[square], 2B.6803-1[square], 2B.6804-1[square], 2B.6805-2[square], 2B.6806-1[square], 2B.6807-1[square], 2B.6808-2[square]
      - Vieuxtemps, Henri, 1820-1881. Concertos, violin, orchestra, no. 4, op. 31, D minor., 1935 March 14; 6 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 6, Disc 215-220)
        In typescript on labels: 14-3-35. Concerto in D Minor. Op. 31 [Parts 1-6] (Vieuztemps)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz; [unidentified orchestra?]
        Gramophone: 2EA.1444-1[square], 2EA.1445-1[square], 2EA.1446-1[square], 2EA.1447-1[square], 2EA.1448-2[square], 2EA.1449-2[square]
      - Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Introduction et rondo capriccioso., 1935 March 18; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 6, Disc 221-222)
        In typescript on labels: 18-3-35. Introduction & Rondo Capriccioso [Parts 1-2] (Saint-Saens)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz; London Philharmonic Orchestra; [John Barbirolli, conductor]
        Gramophone: 2EA.1450-2[square], 2EA.1451-2[square]
    - Box 7: Gramophone, 78 rpm discs
      Barbirolli, John, Sir; Sargent, Malcolm, Sir; Bay, Emanuel; London Philharmonic Orchestra; Rubinstein, Artur; London Symphony Orchestra
      - Wieniawski, Henri, 1835-1880. Concertos, violin, orchestra, no. 2, op. 22, D minor., 1935 March 18; 5 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 7, Disc 223-227)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; London Philharmonic Orchestra
        Gramophone: 2EA.1452-2.[square], 2EA.1453-1.[square], 2EA.1454-2.[square], 2EA.1455-1.[square], 2EA1456-1.[square] (matrix nos. in typescript on label)
      - Szymanowski, Karol, 1882-1937. Król Roger. Pieśń Roksany., 1935 December 4; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 7, Disc 228)
        In typescript on label: Chant de Roxane
        Gramophone: 2EA.2580-1.[square] (matrix no. in typescript on label)
      - Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946. Vida breve. Danza, no. 1; arr., 1935 December 11; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 7, Disc 229)
        In typescript on label: Danse espagnol “La vida breve” (de Falla-Kreisler)
        Gramophone: 2EA.2581-3.[square] (matrix no. in typescript on label)
      - Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946. Canciones populares españolas. Nana – Ibert, Jacques, 1890-1962. Histoires. Petit âne blanc., 1935 December 4; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 7, Disc 230)
        Gramophone: 2EA.2582-2.[square] (matrix no. in typescript on label)
      - Albéniz, Isaac, 1860-1909. Iberia. Puerto; arr., 1935 December 4; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 7, Disc 231)
        Gramophone: 2EA.2583-1.[square] (matrix no. in typescript on label)
      - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonaten und Partiten, violin, BWV 1001-1006. Partita, no. 2., 1935 December 6; 5 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 7, Disc 232-236)
        Gramophone: 2EA.2584-2.[square], 2EA.2585-2.[square], 2EA.2586-1.[square], 2EA.2586-3.[square], 2EA.2591-2.[square] (matrix nos. in typescript on label)
      - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonaten und Partiten, violin, BWV 1001-1006. Partita, no. 2. Chaconne., 1935 December 6; 3 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 7, Disc 237-239)
        Gramophone: 2EA.2592-1.[square], 2EA.2593-1.[square], 2EA.2594-1.[square] (matrix nos. in typescript on label)
      - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonaten und Partiten, violin, BWV 1001-1006. Sonata, no. 3., 1935 December 6; 5 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 7, Disc 240-244)
        Gramophone: 2EA.2595-1.[square], 2EA.2596-1.[square], 2EA.2597-1.[square], 2EA.2598-1.[square], 2EA.2599-3.[square] (matrix nos. in typescript on label)
      - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonaten und Partiten, violin, BWV 1001-1006. Sonata, no. 1. Adagio., 1935 December 11; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 7, Disc 245)
        Gramophone: 2EA.2600-2.[square]
        This disc contains movements 1 only of Sonata no. 1. See Discs 254-256 for movements 2, 3, and 4
      - Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 47, D minor., 1935 December 14; 8 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 7, Disc 246-253)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; London Philharmonic Orchestra; Sir Thomas Beecham, conductor
        Gramophone: 2EA-2818-2[square], 2EA-2819-1[square], 2EA-2820-1[square], 2EA-2821-2[square], 2EA-2822-3[square], 2EA-2823-3a[square], 2EA-2824-3[square], 2EA-2825-2A[square]
      - Bach, Johann Sebastian, 1685-1750. Sonaten und Partiten, violin, BWV 1001-1006. Sonata, no. 1. Selections., 1935 December 11; 3 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 7, Disc 254-256)
        Gramophone: 2EA.3001-1.[square], 2EA.3002-2.[square], 2EA.3003-2.[square]
        These discs contain movements 2, 3, and 4 of Sonata no. 1. See Disc 245 for movement 1
      - Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921. Havanaise., 1937 April 9; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 7, Disc 257-258)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin [with the London Symphony Orchestra; Sir John Barbirolli, conductor]
        Gramophone: 2EA-4744-1a[square], 2EA-4745-1a[square]
      - Sarasate, Pablo de, 1844-1908. Zigeunerweisen; arr., 1937 April 9; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 7, Disc 259-260)
        Gramophone: 2EA-4746-2[square], 2EA-4747-2a[square]
      - Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Nocturnes, piano, op. 62. No. 1., 1937 February 13-1937 February 14; 2 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 7, Disc 261-262)
        Performed by Arthur [sic] Rubinstein, piano
        Gramophone: 2EA.4823-1[square], 2EA.4824-3[square]
      - Chopin, Frédéric, 1810-1849. Nocturnes, piano, op. 48. No. 1., 1937 February 14; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 7, Disc 263)
        Gramophone: 2EA.4828-1[square]
      - Scott, Cyril, 1879-1970. Tallahassee suite. Negro air and dance -- Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963. Mouvements perpétuels [unspecified excerpt]., 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 7, Disc 264)
        Performed byJascha Heifetz, violin; E. Bay, piano
        Gramophone: 2EA.4855-3[square], DB.3213 (Side A); 2EA.4893-2[square], DB.3213 (Side B)
      - Bazzini, Antonio, 1818-1897. Ronde des lutins., 1937 April 9; 12" shellac 78 rpm sound disc (Box 7, Disc 265)
        Gramophone: 2EA.4895-1[square]
      - Vieuxtemps, Henri, 1820-1881. Concertos, violin, orchestra, no. 5, op. 37, A minor., 1947 November 8; 4 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 7, Disc 266-269)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; London Symphony Orchestra; Sir Malcolm Sargent, conductor
        Gramophone: 2EA 12513-1, 2EA 12514-2, 2EA 12515-1, 2EA 12516-2
    - Box 8: Gramophone, 78 rpm discs
      Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961; Susskind, Walter; Moiseiwitsch, Benno; Walton, William, 1902-1983; London Symphony Orchestra; Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Sargent, Malcolm, Sir
      - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, violin, orchestra, K. 218, D major., 1947 November 10; 6 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 8, Disc 270-275)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; The Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Sir Thomas Beecham, conductor
        Gramophone: 2EA 12521-1, 2EA 12522-2, 2EA 12523-2, 2EA 12524-2, 2EA 12525-2, 2EA 12526-1
      - Elgar, Edward, 1857-1934. Concertos, violin, orchestra, op. 61, B minor., 1949 June 7, 1949 June 6, 1949 September 13; 10 12" shellac 78 rpm sound discs (Box 8, Disc 276-285)
        Performed by Jascha Heifetz, violin; London Symphony Orchestra; [Sir Malcolm Sargent, conductor]
        Gramophone: 2EA 13929-2, 2EA 13930-2, 2EA 13931-2, 2EA 13932-1, 2EA 13933-1, 2EA 13934-2, 2EA 13935-4, 2EA 13936-1, 2EA 13937-1, 2EA 13938-2
        Recorded primarily on June 7, 1949 but some portions recorded on June 6 and September 13, 1949